Guide to the Stanford University, Program in American Studies, Honors Theses SC4-3431
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Program in American Studies, honors theses
1991-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Program in American Studies
SC4-3431
2.5 Linear Feet (49 volumes in 5 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in American Studies at Stanford University.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Program in American Studies at Stanford University.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
United States -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. Program in American Studies
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Ballí, Cecilia, Staging culture in Tejano Texas: the public performance of identify in the South Texas Rio Grande Valley., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Carlee, Fertile ground: growing the image of the American farmer., 2009 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Molly, University anti-harassment speech codes: an exmination of the University's interests through a case study analysis., 1991 (Box 1)
  - de Baca, Michael (Miguel), The whip and the cross: the constructed identities of the Penitente brotherhood in New Mexico., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Knize, Megan S., May the winds of freedom blow: the roles and rights of a Stanford Daily newspaper editor., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Krantz, Brandi, Mothers of the Shtetl, daughters of America: representations of mothers and daughters in the fiction and autobiography of early twentieth century Jewish American immigrants., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Lai, David, Into the Dexter gospel: an investigation of Martin Luther King, Jr.'s theology through his sermons, 1953-62., 2008 (Box 1)
  - Liu, Annie En-Yi, Redefining AIDS activism in America: a new wave in the wake of ACT UP., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Reilly, Shane, Changing times, unchanging murals., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Reyna, Renee C., Without color, without equality: reconsidering race in education., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Huston, Ben, Taking fake news seriously: the Daily Show's satirical assault on the American news media., 2005 (Box 2)
  - Sisson, Kelly Joan, Diaspora, Deseos and dead Gringos: Chileno contract laborers and the California Gold Rush., 2003 (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Ivy, Memory and identity in Toni Morrison's Beloved., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Thukral, Riene [Renita Kaul], Back to the neighborhoods: a history of San Jose Unified School District's twenty-five years of desegregation., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Murakawa, Dawnalyn, Taking control: youth and developing identity in the Japanese American relocation centers of the Second World War., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Horn, Margo, Women's history from the void to the margin: an examination of three high school United States history textbooks., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Meador, Jeff, American musical theatre revivals., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Emery, Theodore A., Insurgent nation: SDS and the Economic Research and Action Project, 1963-1965., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Koshy, Tanya, Remodeling resistance: Black civil society and the battle against Baltimore's residential segregation ordinances (1910-1918)., 2006 (Box 2)
  - Levine, Danielle, "Hello, gorgeous": Hollywood, Barbra Streisand, beauty, and the Jewish woman., 2007 (Box 2)
  - McCoy, Lauren, Fourth and inches: the struggle against college football's glass ceiling for minorities., 2006 (Box 2)
  - Narrowe, Meredith, Sundance, Hollywood, and the independent film: the foundations and influence of America's most famous film festival., 2004 (Box 2)
  - Rush, Marny, Sesame Street in the 1990s: the race relations curriculum., 1994 (Box 3)
  - Twist, Allison, Lady Lindy lives: revisiting imaging of Amelia Earhart from the 1920s until today., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Downing, Nancy Farish, How Americo Paredes's literature became a project of humanizing Mexican Americans., 1997 (Box 3)
  - Goodman, Brian, Kral Majales - King of May: Allen Ginsberg and the Czech culture of dissent., 2006 (Box 3)
  - Jacobs, Jeremy, "Out" is "In" -- How Larry David's Seinfeld and Curb Your Enthusiasm made Jewishness "hip" through the blurring of mainstream and Jewish Humor., 2006 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Sonya K., Tradition and change: chicanas rewriting the legend of La Llorona., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Cowan, Brooke A., Richard Rodriguez: a Chicano story, an American story., 1994 (Box 3)
  - Lewis, Patricia Scheiern, Meat art: the aesthetics of flesh (2 v.)., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Monson, Catrice A., Changes in the portrayal of Black women and the family in situation comedies: analyzing representations in "Good Times" and "The Cosby Show"., 1994 or 1995 (Box 3)
  - Lombardi,Brita, Rural ghettoes, changing frontiers -- a case study of out-of-school youth life in poor rural communities., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Brennan, Brian P., A way of being and living: the volunteer experience at El Paso's Annunciation House., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Friedlieb, Linda, Examining the lens of the media: an analysis of historical and newsroom-oriented factors in the newspaper coverage of the deaths at Kent State and Jackson State in May 1970., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Julia, Majority status for 'minority' students: the challenges of desegregation and realities of racial isolation in Redwood City, California., 2001 (Box 4)
  - Schnitz, Katy, "The Winds of Freedom Blow": anti-communism at Stanford University in the 1950s., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Moquino, Trisha Povi, "Indian time: its irresponsible discourse and social ramifications., 1996
  - Archer, Shirley J., In Pursuit of the Public Interest: An Analysis of the Authorization and Impact of the Motor Carriers Act of 1935, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Berger, Evan, The Hummer, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Ross, I Will Not Write My Honors Thesis About The Simpsons, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Follett, Jeffrey, "Let Us Seek the True Commonwealth:" Thought and Policy in The Journal of United Labor, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Holloway, Jonathan S., Defeating Desire While Endeavoring to be the Best: The Conflict Between Professionalism and Pure Sport Ideology in Modern Sports, 1989; 1 folder(s)
  - Saenz, Jessalyn, The Silicon Valley Dream: Popular Renderings and Complicated Realities, 2000; 1 folder(s)
  - Eisenberg, Jonathan, The Battle Over Vista of the Reagan Revolution, 1992; 1 folder(s)
  - Simpson, Annie, "With Their Teeth Still Set on Edge": The Resilience of Plessy in American Public Education, 2001; 1 folder(s)
  - Tirres, Andrea L., Negotiating Borders: The Case of Operation Hold the Line in El Paso, Texas, 1999; 1 folder(s)
  - Tyndall, William F., Business and the Clean Air Act of 1970: An Analysis of A Revisionist Interpretation of Liberal Reform, 1979; 1 folder(s)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2015-039
  - Robins, Will,"Challenges of illustrating slavery in nineteenth century American literature", 2014
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Mac, Ryan, "The long history of ROTC at Stanford: from precursors to the present", 2011 May 16 (Box 1)